SANTHIYA JEEVANANDHAM

7358298014 & santhiyajeevanandham@gmail.com https://santhiya-18.github.io/Santhiya.com/

SUMMARY

3.2 years of professional development experience, Expertise lies in the area of Java, UI/UX development, and frontend engineering. Proficiency in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and Angular. Advanced understanding of OOPS. Good work experience in Software Development Lifecycle and Agile Environment. Good at Code review and design review.

EXPERIENCE

MERCEDES-BENZ RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT

DECEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

Software Developer

- · I am on the front end team that builds a dashboard to manage and track all after sales car information
- Re Designed Web Components
- · Closely working with the backend team to create the best possible user experience
- Understood complex codes, adapted quickly and sorted pending bug.

Technologies: Angular, JavaScript, Figma

L&T INFOTECH

NOVEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2021

Software Engineer

- Worked closely with design, product management, and development teams to create elegant, usable, responsive and interactive interfaces across multiple devices.
- Turned UI/UX designs into prototypes, creating awesome interactions from designs, writing reusable content modules and maintainability of the code.
- Designed and Developed the Frontend side of the Integrated Assessment Platform single-handedly in 48 hours.
- Led a team of 4 to develop a strategic web application for recruiting candidates, identifying job criticality and opportunities which decreases workflow up to 30%.
- Conceptualized original ideas that bring simplicity, best data visualization and user-friendliness to reduce complex workload.
- Re-Designed and developed the Frontend side of ACE (Automation COE Center of Excellence) Portal.

Technologies: Angular, Liferay, Java, Figma, Adobe XD

AWARDS

SPOTLIGHT - FOR DEVELOPING BEST SOLUTIONS (APRIL 2021)

PAT ON THE BACK - FOR OUTSTANDING PERFORMANCE AND DEDICATION (DEC 2020)

OUR PRIDE - FOR AUTOMATION KPI DASHBOARD ROLL OUR (AUGUST 2020)

SKILLS

Java, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, CSS GRID system, Angular, REACT/REDUX(Basic), JavaScript, UI/UX, Adobe Illustrator, Figma, MYSQL

LEADERSHIP & RESPONSIBILITY

TRAINING COORDINATOR - LTI AUTOMATION CENTER OF EXCELLENCE | 2021 - PRESENT EDITORIAL BOARD CHAIRMAN - DISTRICT ROTARACT COUNCIL 3232 | 2018 -2019

PRESIDENT & COMMUNITY SERVICE DIRECTOR - STELLA MARIS COLLEGE | 2017 - 2018

CLASS REPRESENTATIVE - STELLA MARIS COLLEGE | 2015 - 2016

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATIONS - STELLA MARIS COLLEGE, CHENNAI | 2015 - 2018

COURSE WORK

Google UX Design Professional Certificate, Front end framework - angular & React/Redux, DATA STRUCTURES AND Algorithm, mongodb

GET IN TOUCH!